<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Haywire</title>
    <description>Haywire ia
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/haywire/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/haywire/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 02:41:41 +0530</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 02:41:41 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>For The Love of Code</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;What do you imagine when I say “artist”? What image comes up in your mind when I say a “creative” person? A poet? Maybe a painter, or maybe a musician. But who decides what art is? Why do we limit the definition of creativity to these few areas?
Take any contemporary movie that discusses the debate between arts and science. It features a doctor/engineer who wanted to pursue arts but couldn’t for whatsoever reasons. Why do we automatically assume that these fields are the exact opposite of what creativity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding is one such example. When you think of hobbies that require inspiration, imagination or creativity, this would certainly not be one of the contenders on that list. But think about it. An artist has colors and instruments, a programmer has his favorite hardware and languages. You can write a generic piece of code from a textbook that would meet the requirements. OR, you could find the inspiration to find the exact fit. The optimal solution, tailor-made for that problem. A solution that solicits a level of satisfaction that makes you giddy with happiness. You can read it like a poem and watch it work like a perfectly synchronized orchestra. To me, coding is an artform. Let no one tell you otherwise.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/haywire/for-the-love-of-code/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/haywire/for-the-love-of-code/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Soul Food</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Why is it that we sometimes feel more connected with a singer you’ve never met, than with the company of people who may have known you for years. Why is it that these symphonies hold more truth than any advice you’ve ever received?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what your mood is, there will always be a lyric to match it. Some moods might solicit the company of real humans, but most of them will tease your mind until you allow them to drown into the dulcet tones and dancing notes of an instrument.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The soul will demand the resonating sound from the wind dancing in a flute, the conversations between guitar strings brought closer and pulled apart from each other in a playful rhythm, and the singing face of the drum as it meets with its wooden companions. 
All these voices feel so much more like home than the presence of your own species.
Does that make you weird? To be more comfortable with instruments of wood, and lyrics from a stranger? Maybe. But who cares? When your body demands food, so does the soul. And that’s where the tunes come in. Blowing through the wind to your radio, or in combinations of a gazillion 0s and 1s on your laptop, finally finding their way to your ears. Travelling through your synapses and into the little corner that’s the gateway to your soul. Music, becoming soul food.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/haywire/soul-food/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/haywire/soul-food/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Do We Write</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Why do we write?&lt;/em&gt; Why do we feel the need to force our emotions to flow out in the permutations and combinations of 26 simple letters? To try and tame the flurry of thoughts swirling around in our head, for fleeting moments, just so we can channel them out of our body, embodied by drops of ink on a piece of paper?
Sometimes it’s to broadcast a message to people, sometimes it’s meant for someone in particular, and other times? Other times its meant for someone a lot closer to home. For yourself. Because when those muddled thoughts start feeling so alien that you feel like a guest in your own head, the gift of language comes to your rescue. The letters prance in like knights trying to tame the wild thoughts wreaking havoc in your mind, and ride through your quill all the way till they finally come to rest on that diminutive sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then you read them. Silently. Almost as if they were written by a stranger. And you realize, that maybe it really is. That maybe it’s true that it’s not you whose thoughts you’re hearing. It’s the cries of the little creature sitting behind the controls to a vehicle you call your body. And you’re just a spectator with the illusion of control. And words are your only outlet to the real world, the only way to let your presence be known. And maybe the only way to communicate with the guy in the driver’s seat. To communicate with your &lt;em&gt;self&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 23 May 2016 00:00:00 +0530</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/haywire/why-do-we-write/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/haywire/why-do-we-write/</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
